PRITHVIRAJ DESHMANE

1857 Lincoln St Seaside CA 93955 prithvirajdeshmane@gmail.com 585-705-6702

SUMMARY

Senior team lead and software engineer with 15+ years of experience in all stages of Software Development Life Cycle. Excellent communication and interpersonal skills and a strong technical aptitude. Experienced in leading teams, training and mentoring, documentation, and analyzing project requirements and collaborating with cross-functional teams.

EMPLOYMENT AUTHORIZATION: Green Card holder

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY:

QA Lead - Apple (2017-2023 via Hogarth CA, 2015-2017 via MindSource Inc.)

- Collaborated closely with business, brand and 5+ cross-functional teams, analyzed requirements and schedules, created and executed test plans covering 30+ metrics per project, and 6000+ issues, enhancements, changes and updates overall
- Devised automated and manual testing tools leading to increased productivity
- Managed, trained and mentored team members (8+ team members at any time, 50+ overall)
- Created and maintained documentation for Development, Testing and Release teams and for 150+ Stakeholders to aid tracking and decision making
- Ensured project deliverables met functional and usability requirements, reduced security risks, provided support during production releases and post-deployment warranty phases

QA Engineer - Apple (2014-2015 via MindSource Inc.)

- System test, regression test multiple simultaneous Marcom platforms and projects
- Recommend solutions and verify fixes pertaining to functionality, analytics, accessibility, content manipulation, audio, video, gallery and miscellaneous usability to ensure highest level of user experience

IT Applications Programmer - Progressive Insurance Inc. (2010-2013)

- Developed innovative device for customized usage-based insurance quotes
- Developed enhancements for time-critical policy rollouts
- Collaborated with business and brand to analyze requirements and conducted code reviews
- Created and maintained technical documentation and conducted knowledge transfers

Software Engineer - EDS, Pune, India — 2006-2007

- Develop, enhance and maintain dashboard applications for DaimlerChrysler
- Provide support, feedback and conduct design discussions for iterative enhancements

Software Engineering Intern - National Informatics Center, Pune, India — 2006

 Design, develop and test a corporate network security application with a firewall and optimized intranet bandwidth management system

EDUCATION

- MS Computer Science Rochester Institute of Technology, Rochester, NY: 2007 2013
- BE Computer Engineering University of Pune, India: 2001 2006

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Programming languages: Java, Python, HTML, CSS, JavaScript
- Application Packages: Git, Microsoft Office Suite, SharePoint, HP Quality Center
- Proprietary to Apple: Radar, Terminal, Numbers, Pages, Keynote, Kaleidoscope, Charles
- Excellent relation-building, communication, collaboration, conflict resolution and risk assessment